Guide to the Völkerkundliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft collection on Native Americans 1962-1984
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Völkerkundliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft collection on Native Americans
1962-1984
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0251VolkArbeit
Völkerkundliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft (Germany)
.6 linear feet
This is a collection of discussion papers, mostly in German, relating to Indians of British Columbia and the United States. The collection was produced as the result of an exchange relationship between the Northwest Coast Anthropological Archives of the Völkerkundliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft in Germany and the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies.
This is a collection of discussion papers, mostly in German, relating to Indians of British Columbia and the United States.
The collection was produced as the result of an exchange relationship between the Northwest Coast Anthropological Archives of the Völkerkundliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft in Germany and the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies.
The collection is open to the public.
Donated by the Northwest Coast Anthropological Archives of the Völkerkundliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft, circa 1982.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Indians of North America--History; Indians of North America--Canada--History
Native Americans
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Lexikostatistiche Methoden, by Karl-Heinz Gursky, 1962 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Das Ibero-Amerikanische Institut Berlin – Seine Entstehung und Entwicklung, by Hans-Joanchim Bock, 1964 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Bemerkungen zur Beothunk-Sprache, by Karl-Heinz Gursky, 1964 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Sinti, der erste Mensch Eine Schopfungssage der Kioway-Indianer, by Albert S. Gatsche, 1965 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Tonawanda Seneca New Year and Midwinter Rite, by Michael G. Johnson, 1965 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Zur Frage Der Historischen Stellung Der Yuki-Sprachfamilie, by Karl-Heinz Gursky, 1965 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Das Proto-Hoka-Subtiaba-Wort fur “Kaninchen,” by Karl-Heinz Gursky, 1965 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Einige ethnographisce Notizen uber dis Kiowa-Apache, by Uwe Johannsen, 1965 (Box-folder 1/8)
- Seneca New Year Festivals of Bygone Times, by J.C. Hayes, 1965 (Box-folder 1/9)
- Identity and Demography of the Cree Indians, by Michael G. Johnson, 1965 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Abriss der Politischen Geschichte der Delawaren-Indianer, by Uwe Johannsen, 1966 (Box-folder 1/11)
- Beitrage Zur Sprachwissenschaft und Volkerkunde der Nordamerikanischen Indianer:I, 1966 (Box-folder 1/12)
- Beitrage Zur Sprachwissenschaft und Volkerkunde der Nordamerikanischen Indianer:II, 1967 (Box-folder 1/13)
- Bericht von Einer Kondolenz-Zeremonie Bei Den Cayuga-Irokesen, by Gunther Michelson, 1967 (Box-folder 1/14)
- Einige Bemerkungen Zu Den Bevolkerungszahlen der Nordamerikanischen Sprachfamilien, by Karl-Heinz Gursky, 1968 (Box-folder 1/15)
- Neuere Referenzliteratur uber die amerikanischen Indianer zuzammengestellt, by Uwe Johannsen, 1968 (Box-folder 1/16)
- Beitrage Zur Sprachwissenschaft und Volkerkunde der Nordamerikanischen Indianer: III, 1969 (Box-folder 1/17)
- Roland B. Dixon: Zoque and Xinca Compared With Penutian by Karl-Heinz Gursky, 1969 (Box-folder 1/18)
- Catawba Tribal History, by John Cadwalader, 1969 (Box-folder 1/19)
- Benjamin L. Whorf: The Uto-Aztecan Stock/Azteco-Tanoan/Macro-Penutian, by Karl-Heinz Gursky, 1969 (Box-folder 1/20)
- Beitrage zur Aprachwissenschaft und Volkerkunde der nordamerikaniscen Indianer:IV, 1970 (Box-folder 1/21)
- Notizen zur Architektur der Bella Coola-Indianer, by Uwe Johannsen, 1978 (Box-folder 1/22)
- Notes on the Early History of the Nicola Valley, by James A. Teit, 1979 (Box-folder 1/23)
- Process of Change from Mtrilineal to Patrilineal Inhertance as Illustrated in Building, Ownership,and Transmission of Houses and House Sites in a Tsimshian Village, by Amelia Susman, Viola E. Garfield, William Beynon, 1979 (Box-folder 1/24)
- Zur Entwicklung der Gesellschaftsordnung Bei Den Bella Coola an der Nordwestkuste Nordamerikas, by Julija Pavlovna Averkieva, 1980 (Box-folder 1/25)
- Salmon Spirits and World Renewal Concepts of the Kwakiutl, by Finn Wilhelmsen, 1980 (Box-folder 1/26)
- The Indo-European Homeland in Anatolia, by Grover Krantz, 1981 (Box-folder 1/27)
- Ethnohistoric Study of Haida Acculturation, by Ruth Elaine Smith, 1982 (Box-folder 1/28)
- Ethnohistoric Study of Haida Acculturation, Part 2, by Ruth Elaine Smith, 1983 (Box-folder 1/29)
- Ethnohistoric Study of Haida Acculturation, Part 3, by Ruth Elaine Smith, 1984 (Box-folder 1/30)
- The Origins Of Nootkan Whaling, by John Dewhirst, 1982 (Box-folder 1/31)
- The Potlatch in Anthropological Theory, by Marianne Bolscher, 1982 (Box-folder 1/32)
- Potlatching, Warfare, and Raiding Among the Southern Kwakiutl, 1982 (Box-folder 1/33)
- A Historian of the Tlingit, by David E. Conrad, 1984 (Box-folder 1/34)